Finding Aid for the Norman Cousins Papers LSC.1385
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Volume 5
  - Subject files
    - Physicians
      - Kling, Arthur (Box 1776)
      - Kroger, William S. (Box 1776)
      - Looney, Gerald (Box 1776)
      - Maloney, James J. (Box 1776)
      - Pelletier, Kenneth (Box 1776)
      - Pomeroy, Dr. (Box 1776)
      - Ricketts, Robert (Box 1776)
      - Rimland, Bernard (Box 1776)
      - Salk, Dr. Jonas (Box 1776)
      - Sandblom, Philip (Box 1776)
      - Stehlin, John (Box 1776)
      - Sakalosky, George (Box 1776)
      - Stone, Irwin (Box 1776)
      - Usen, Gene (Box 1776)
      - Bahnson (Box 1776, Box 1777)
        includes Bahnson Festschrift
      - Bergland, Richard (Box 1778)
      - Borysenko, Joan (Box 1778)
      - Vellore, India (Dr. Paul Brand) (Box 1778)
      - Brod, Dr. - UCLA Ext. (Box 1778)
      - Bulloch, Dr. Karen (Box 1815)
      - Cassileth, Barrie R. (Box 1778)
      - Edna McConnell - Clark Foundation (Box 1778)
      - Debakey (Box 1779)
      - Elkes, Joel (Box 1779, Box 1780)
      - Engel, Dr. George (Box 1780)
      - Kleeman, Dr. Chas. (Box 1780, Box 1781)
      - Menninger (Box 1781)
      - Miller, Neal (Box 1781)
      - Pritikin (Box 1781)
      - Rea, Dr. W.S. (Box 1781)
      - Selye, Dr. Hans (Box 1781, Box 1782)
      - Solomon, Dr. George (Box 1782)
      - Spector, Dr. Norvera Herbert (Box 1783)
      - Towers, Bernard (Box 1783)
      - Udelman, Drs. Harold & Donna (Box 1783)
      - Wallerstein, Robert S. (Box 1783)
    - War/peace
      - Arms control (Box 1784)
      - Arms race (Box 1784)
      - Center for Defense Information (Box 1785)
      - The Defense Monitor (Box 1785)
      - Center for War/Peace Studies (Box 1785)
      - Committee for National Security (Box 1785)
      - Defense (Box 1785)
      - Nuclear arms race ad (Box 1785)
      - Healing of Nations material (Box 1785)
      - Nuclear arms race material for speeches (Box 1786)
      - Nuclear disarmament (Box 1786)
      - Nuclear war consequences (conf. report) (Box 1786)
      - Nuclear war/nuclear freeze material (Box 1786, Box 1787)
      - Peace projects (Box 1788)
      - Peace plans - Rosenfeld, Forsberg, etc. (Box 1788)
      - Commission to study the organization of peace (Box 1788)
      - For RAF (Box 1788)
      - Strategic Defense Initiative (Box 1789)
      - Saturday Review editorials - possible use in RAF (Box 1789)
      - Harris Woffard (Box 1789)
  - Telephone logs
    - [48 spiral notebooks], 8/78-10/88 (Box 1320, Box 1321)
      missing 12/30/86-7/14/87, 8/18/87-1/18/88
  - Trip files
    - Philippines trip with H.H. Humphrey, 1965-1966 (Box 1322,1814, Folder 1-3)
      (one folder in box 1814)
    - Lebanon, 1972? (Box 1322, Folder 4)
    - Israel, 1978 (Box 1322, Folder 5-7)
    - Corresp. European Trip, 1948 (Box 1322, Folder 8)
    - Japan Trip, 1966? (Box 1322, Folder 9)
    - China, 1979? (Box 1323,1736, Folder 1-4)
      (one folder in box 1736)
  - Trip files and logs
    - [trip files arranged chronologically], 1988 (Box 1800, Box 1801, Box 1802, Box 1803)
  - Unsorted
    - [to be sorted] (Box 1324, Box 1325)
      includes some Clarence Darrow publications
  - Videotapes
    - [tapes 1-9] (Box 1327)
      individual listing of tapes in Appendix II
    - [tapes 10-35] (Box 1328)
    - [tapes 36-54] (Box 1329)
    - [tapes 55-72] (Box 1330)
    - [tapes 73-98] (Box 1331)
    - [tapes 100-123] (Box 1332)
    - [Corresp. regarding making of video/audio tapes] (Box 1333)
  - World Federalist Association
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1980 (Box 1403, Folder 1)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1981 (Box 1403, Folder 2)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1982 (Box 1403, Folder 3)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1983 (Box 1403, Folder 4)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1984 (Box 1403, Folder 5)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1985 (Box 1403, Folder 6)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1986 (Box 1404, Folder 1)
    - WFA annual files (correspondence, programs), 1987 (Box 1404, Folder 2)
    - WFA Board Mtg., 1990 (Box 1404, Folder 3)
- Additions, 1985
  - Trip Files: (Box 632)
    - - SALINA KANSAS: Marymount College of Kansas, MAY 10, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 1)
    - - NEW YORK CITY: Society of Authors and Journalists, MAY 9, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 2)
    - - DURANGO COLORADO: Kettering Foundation Board Meeting., MAY 6-8, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 3)
    - - LOS ANGELES SINAI TEMPLE: University of Judaism, MAY 4, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 4)
    - - ANAHEIM: Association of Western Hospitals, APRIL 29, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 5)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Cancer Advisory Council, APRIL 22, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 6)
    - - UC IRVINE: Environmental Development Health Colloquium, APRIL 8, 1982 (Box 632, Folder 7)
    - - WINSTON-SALEM, NORTH CAROLINA: Wake Forest University - Bowman School of Medicine, MARCH 26, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 8)
    - - NEW YORK: Columbia University - National Magazine Awards., MARCH 25-26, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 9)
    - - ANAHEIM: Stress and Catastrophic Illness Meeting., MARCH 22, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 10)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Holmes Center Annual Symposium., MARCH 21, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 11)
    - - MOSCOW: Dartmouth Interim Meeting, MARCH 15-18, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 12)
    - - DALLAS: Mountain View College, MARCH 12, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 13)
    - - NEW YORK CITY: Cornell University Medical College., MARCH 9, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 14)
    - - PHILADELPHIA: Albert Einstein Medical Center., MARCH 8, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 15)
    - - WASHINGTON, D.C. World Federalists Association., MARCH 6-8, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 16)
    - - PHILADELPHIA: Thomas Jefferson Medical College, MARCH 5, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 17)
    - - HARBOR-UCLA MEDICAL CENTER: Grand Rounds (OB-GYN), MARCH 2, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 18)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Writers' Conference - Loyola Marymount University., FEBRUARY 28, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 19)
    - - COVINA: Chapman College, FEBRUARY 18, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 20)
    - - SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA: Sonoma County Medical Association., FEBRUARY 12, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 21)
    - - SANTA ANA, CALIFORNIA: Santa Ana-Tustin Community Hospital., FEBRUARY 6, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 22)
    - - WILSHIRE EBELL: Southern California Counseling Center, FEBRUARY 5, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 23)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Psychologists-L.A. City Schools., FEBRUARY 2, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 24)
    - - SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS: Trinity University., JANUARY 30, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 25)
    - - WESTWOOD: Society of Methodist Men, JANUARY 26, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 26)
    - - SAN FRANCISCO: Woody Clark Productions. Film., JANUARY 22-23, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 27)
    - - KANSAS CITY: U.M.K.C. Consultants to Chancellor., JANUARY 19-20, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 28)
    - - UCLA NPI AUD.: Hospital and Clinics Series: Health Wise., JANUARY 18, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 29)
    - - MALIBU: Pepperdine University, JANUARY 16, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 30)
    - - WASHINGTON D.C.: Veterans Administration, JANUARY 14-16, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 31)
    - - NEW YORK CITY: "Open Mind" T.V. Show., JANUARY 13, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 32)
    - - MIAMI: Peers, Incorporated Nurses Seminar, JANUARY 8-9, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 33)
    - - BOCA RATON, FLORIDA: Women's Club of Royal Palm Yacht and Golf., JANUARY 7, 1981 (Box 632, Folder 34)
    - - USC: Friends of Music Dinner, DECEMBER 7, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 35)
    - - BOSTON: Harvard Medical School, DECEMBER 4, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 36)
    - - BOSTON: American Cancer Society, DECEMBER 3, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 37)
    - - LOMA LINDA, CALIFORNIA: Loma Linda University School of Medicine., NOVEMBER 30, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 38)
    - - SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA: Book and Author Event., NOVEMBER 21-22, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 39)
    - - CHICAGO: Blue Cross-Blue Shield, NOVEMBER 19-20, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 40)
    - - UCLA: Pharmacology 201 Guest Lecture, NOVEMBER 18, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 41)
    - - BRENTWOOD: Brentwood Presbyterian Church, NOVEMBER 16, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 42)
    - - RANCHO MIRAGE: Eisenhower Medical Center, NOVEMBER 6, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 43)
    - - KANSAS CITY: University of Missouri, Kansas City., NOVEMBER 5, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 44)
    - - UCLA: The Engineer and Society, NOVEMBER 4, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 45)
    - - NEW YORK: Synagogue Council of America, OCTOBER 30, 1980 (Box 632, Folder 46)
    - - LOS ANGELES: California Magazine Day, OCTOBER 29, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 1)
    - - WASHINGTON D.C.: D.C. Medical Society, OCTOBER 26, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 2)
    - - SANTA MONICA CHRISTIAN CHURCH., OCTOBER 19, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 3)
    - - LOS ANGELES: National Association of Social Workers - L.A. Chapter., OCTOBER 18, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 4)
    - - WACO, TEXAS: Baylor University., OCTOBER 16, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 5)
    - - HOUSTON: Baylor College of Medicine, OCTOBER 15, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 6)
    - - HOUSTON: Congregation Beth Israel, OCTOBER 15, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 7)
    - - CLAREMONT: Pilgrim Place Dedication, OCTOBER 12, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 8)
    - - SANTA BARBARA: Hutchins Center, OCTOBER 8, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 9)
    - - SAN FRANCISCO: Council on Learning, OCTOBER 9, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 10)
    - - TORRANCE, CALIFORNIA: Harbor General Hospital., OCTOBER 7, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 11)
    - } UCLA EXTENSION SERIES, OCTOBER 7,14,21,28 (Box 633, Folder 12)
    - }, NOVEMBER 4,11,18 (Box 633)
    - - FLINT, MICHIGAN: Ruth Mott Fund - Board Meeting., SEPTEMBER 29, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 13)
    - - Jerusalem International Seminar on Hospital Pharmacy., AUGUST 27, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 14)
    - - SAN FRANCISCO: "Sunday Times" [T.V. Show], AUGUST 14, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 15)
    - - SAN FRANCISCO: "Over Easy" [T.V. Show], AUGUST 14, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 16)
    - - BERKELEY: Lawrence Livermore Laboratories, AUGUST 14, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 17)
    - - HILLCREST/CENTURY PLAZA: Chief Executives Forum, AUGUST 12, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 18)
    - - David Letterman Show, AUGUST 11, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 19)
    - - SHELBURNE, VERMONT. Shelbrune Farms/E(llen) Rockefeller., AUGUST 9, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 20)
    - - CAPE COD: Continuing Education Institute, AUGUST 4-8, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 21)
    - - UCLA: Dr. Roy Menninger, JULY 22, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 22)
    - - WESTWOOD: Voluntary Euthanasia, JULY 16, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 23)
    - - IRVINE: U.C. Irvine College of Medicine, JULY 16, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 24)
    - - SANTA MONICA: Rand Seminar, JULY 15, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 25)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Temple Isiah, JULY 10, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 26)
    - - UCLA: Hugh O'Brian Youth Foundation, JULY 6, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 27)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Humanitas Prize Luncheon, JULY 2, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 28)
    - - SAN PEDRO: San Pedro Peninsula Hospital, JUNE 28, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 29)
    - - SANTA BARBARA: Writers' Conference, JUNE 25-27, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 30)
    - - WALNUT CREEK, CALIFORNIA: John Muir Medical Film Festival, JUNE 22, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 31)
    - - Commonwealth Club of California, JUNE 20, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 32)
    - - 2644 CEDARS: Dr. Rene Dubos., JUNE 19, 1980 (Box 633, Folder 33)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Round Table West, JUNE 19, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 1)
    - - KALAMAZOO, MICHIGAN. Kalamazoo College; and Midl and Michigan., JUNE 14, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 2)
    - - BEVERLY WILSHIRE: General Surgery Banquet, JUNE 7, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 3)
    - - NPI: Grand Rounds on Humor, JUNE 6, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 4)
    - - LA CROSSE, WISCONSIN: Amer. Holis. Medical Association., JUNE 6-11, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 5)
    - - UCLA FACULTY CENTER: Doctoral Alumni Association Graduate School of Education of UCLA., JUNE 5, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 6)
    - - WESTWOOD: American Lupus Society, JUNE 3, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 7)
    - - LOS ANGELES: USC - U.N. Reform Conference, JUNE 1, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 8)
    - - UCLA: Open House - Dr. Mellinkoff., JUNE 1, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 9)
    - - CLEVELAND: Case Western Commencement, MAY 28, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 10)
    - - INDIANAPOLIS: Economic Club of Indianapolis, MAY 27, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 11)
    - - PASADENA: Art Center For Design, MAY 23, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 12)
    - - LOS ANGELES: UCLA Nursing Alumni, MAY 21, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 13)
    - - PASADENA: Throop Memorial Church, MAY 18, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 14)
    - - TUCSON, ARIZONA: University of Arizona Medical School., MAY 16, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 15)
    - - BALTIMORE, MARYLAND: Johns Hopkins University, MAY 13, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 16)
    - - UCLA FACULTY CLUB: Clinical Faculty Annual Dinner., MAY 14, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 17)
    - - WASHINGTON, D.C.: VA - Dr. Donald Custis, MAY 12, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 18)
    - - LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY: University of Louisville School of Medicine Commencement., MAY 11, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 19)
    - - DENVER: University of Colorado Commencement., MAY 10, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 20)
    - - SCHOOL OF PUBLIC HEALTH, UCLA: Health Services Research Graduate Seminar., MAY 7, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 21)
    - - WESTWOOD: AOA UCLA Honor Medical Society, MAY 6, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 22)
    - - POMONA: Pomona Valley Community Hospital, MAY 6, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 23)
    - - SAN FRANCISCO: UCSF Psych. Aspects of Med. Practice., MAY 4, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 24)
    - - JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA: Kettering Board, MAY 1-2, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 25)
    - - WESTWOOD: Parkinsonians, APRIL 28, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 26)
    - - WOODLAND HILLS: Temple Aliyah, APRIL 28, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 27)
    - - SAN FRANCISCO: Cancer Advisory Council, APRIL 23, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 28)
    - - CHICAGO: AMA 76th Congress on Med. Education., APRIL 24, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 29)
    - - LOS ANGELES: Psychiatry 101 Dinner., APRIL 22, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 30)
    - - SAN DIEGO: National University Extension Association, APRIL 21, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 31)
    - - SAN MARINO: USC Friends of Music, APRIL 20, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 32)
    - - WEST LOS ANGELES: American Cancer Society, APRIL 19, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 33)
    - - UCLA DICKSON AUDITORIUM: Holistic Medicine and Conven. Therapy (Med. and Soci. Forum), APRIL 17, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 34)
    - - UCLA: Patient Education, APRIL 16, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 35)
    - - SEPULVEDA, CALIFORNIA: Veteran's Hospital, APRIL 15, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 36)
    - - HOUSTON: Dr. Stehlin, APRIL 11, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 37)
    - - LOS ANGELES: PDE Medical Fraternity., APRIL 12, 1980 (Box 634, Folder 38)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 635, Box 636)
  - Teacher's College, International Cooperation Year (Box 637)
  - Saturday Review Clipping files, Correspondence (Box 638)
  - Saturday Review Clipping files, Correspondence (Box 639, Box 640, Box 641)
  - Air Pollution, 1966 (Box 644, Box 645, Box 646, Box 647)
  - International Cooperation Year (Box 648, Box 649, Box 650)
  - U.N. Peace Organizations, United World Federalists, 1950's-1970's. (Box 651)
  - Saturday Review Correspondence, Subscriptions (Box 652)
  - U.N. Peace Organizations, United World Federalists, 1950s-1970s (Box 653, Box 654)
  - Trip Files, 1976 (Box 655, Box 656, Box 657)
  - Trip Files, 1969-1970 (Box 658, Box 659, Box 660)
  - Trip Files, 1971-1972 (Box 661, Box 662)
  - Trip Files, Trip Files, 1969-1970 1972-1973 (Box 663)
  - Trip Files, 1973-1974 (Box 664)
  - Trip Files, 1971-1972 (Box 665, Box 666)
  - Trip Files, Saturday Review Possible Investors, 1971-1972 (Box 667)
  - Saturday Review Possible Investors (Box 668)
  - Trip Files, 1973-1974 (Box 669)
  - Trip Files, 1971-1972 (Box 670, Box 671)
  - Teacher's College (Box 672, Box 673)
  - Teacher's College, International Cooperation Year (Box 674)
  - International Cooperation Year (Box 675)
  - Kress Foundation (Box 676, Box 677, Box 678)
  - Trip Files, 1975 (Box 679)
  - Trip Files, 1974-1975 (Box 680)
  - Trip Files, 1977-1979 (Box 681, Box 682, Box 683)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 684, Box 685, Box 686)
  - Trip Files, 1977-1979 (Box 687, Box 688)
  - Trip Files; Trip Files, 1976 1977-1979 (Box *689)
  - Saturday Review/World Correspondence (Box 690, Box 691, Box 692)
  - Saturday Review/World Correspondence, Pamphlets, reprints, background materials. (Box 693)
  - Pamphlets, reprints, background materials (Box 694, Box 695)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 696, Box 697, Box 698)
  - Saturday Review Correspondence, Subscriptions (Box 699, Box 700, Box 701, Box 702)
  - Trip Files, 1973-1974 (Box 703, Box 704)
  - Trip Files, 1974, 1977-1979 (Box 705, Box 706, Box 707)
  - Trip Files, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1974, 1977-1979 (Box 708)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 709, Box 710, Box 711)
  - Trip Files, 1979-1980 (Box 712)
  - Trip Files, 1979-1980 (Box 713)
  - Trip Files, 1979-1980 (Box 714)
  - Trip Files, 1979-1980 (Box 715)
  - background materials and Correspondence, 1948 (Box 716)
  - background materials and Correspondence, 1948 (Box 717)
  - background materials and Correspondence, 1948 (Box 718)
  - Air Pollution, 1966 (Box 719)
  - Air Pollution Saturday Review Clipping files, Correspondence, 1966 (Box 720)
  - Saturday Review Clipping files, Correspondence (Box 721)
  - World/Business (Box 722)
  - World/Business (Box 723)
  - World/Business (Box 724)
  - World/Business (Box 725)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 726)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 727)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 728)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 729)
  - [oversize] Correspondence - fiscal UCLA Library Administrative Manual, 1971-72, 1970-71 (Box 730)
  - Audio Tapes: (Box 731)
    - I. Palmer discussion - Holes 1-2
    - II. Palmer discussion - Holes 3-5 + begin 6
    - IV. Holes 8-9/finish
    - V. Bermuda Dunes - Holes 1-2 + begin 3
    - VI. Holes 4-5 + half of 6
    - VII. Holes 7-9 + finish
  - Trip Files, 1973-1974 (Box 732)
  - Trip Files, 1973-1974 (Box 733)
  - Saturday Review Possible Investors, business (Box 734)
  - Saturday Review Possible Investors, business (Box 735)
  - Saturday Review Possible Investors, business (Box 736)
  - Saturday Review/Classifieds (Box 737)
  - Saturday Review/Classifieds (Box 738)
  - Saturday Review/Classifieds (Box 739)
  - Saturday Review/Classifieds (Box 740)
  - World War II Papers (Box 741)
  - World War II Papers (Box 742)
  - World War II Papers (Box 743)
  - World War II Papers (Box 744)
  - Vietnam Research (Box 745)
  - Vietnam Research (Box 746)
  - Vietnam Research (Box 747)
  - Vietnam Research (Box 748)
  - United World Federalists (Box 749)
  - United World Federalists (Box 750)
  - United World Federalists; UWF/World Government (Box 751)
  - United World Federalists/World Government (Box 752)
  - United World Federalists/World Government (Box 753)
  - United World Federalists/World Government (Box 754)
  - Saturday Review/World Correspondence (Box 755)
  - Saturday Review/World Correspondence (Box 756)
  - Saturday Review/World Correspondence (Box 757)
  - United Nations/United World Federalists (Box 758)
  - United Nations/United World Federalists (Box 759)
  - United World Federalists (Box 760)
  - United World Federalists Publications/Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 761)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 762)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 763)
  - Charles Kettering Foundation (Box 764)
  - Old newspapers (Box 765)
  - Old newspapers (Box 766)
  - Old newspapers (Box 767)
  - International Cooperation Year (Box 768)
  - International Cooperation Year (Box 769)
  - International Cooperation Year (FRAGILE MATERIAL) (Box 770)
  - International Cooperation Year (FRAGILE MATERIAL) (Box 771)
  - World War II photos (Box 772)
  - World War II photos (Box 773)
  - World War II photos (Box 774)
  - World War II photos, pamphlets (Box 775)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 776)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 777)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 778)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 779)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 780)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 781)
  - International Cooperation Year (DAMAGED MATERIAL) (Box 782)
  - International Cooperation Year (DAMAGED MATERIAL) (Box 783)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 784)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 785)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 786)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 787)
  - United Nations/World Association of World Federalists (Box 788)
  - World Federalists Association; New Directions, (1976) (Box 789)
  - World Federalists Association; New Directions, (1976) (Box 790)
  - World Federalists Association; New Directions, (1976) (Box 791)
  - World Federalists Association; New Directions, (1976) (Box 792)
  - Saturday Review Classifieds
  - Saturday Review Classifieds (Box 793)
  - Saturday Review Classifieds (Box 794)
  - Saturday Review Classifieds (Box 795)
  - Saturday Review Classifieds (Box 796)
  - Nuclear Disarmament/Civil Defense (Box 797)
  - Nuclear Disarmament/Civil Defense (Box 798)
  - Nuclear Disarmament/Civil Defense (Box 799)
  - Nuclear Disarmament/Civil Defense (Box 800)
  - Nuclear Disarmament/Civil Defense (Box 801)
  - Nuclear Disarmament/Civil Defense (Box 802)
  - World Association of World Federalists, New Directions (Box 803)
  - World Association of World Federalists, New Directions (Box 804)
  - World Association of World Federalists, New Directions (Box 805)
  - World Association of World Federalists, New Directions (Box 806)
  - World Association of World Federalists, New Directions (Box 807)
  - United World Federalists, 1953-54 (Box 808)
  - United World Federalists, 1953-54 (Box 809)
  - United World Federalists, 1953-54 (Box 810)
  - United World Federalists, 1953-54 (Box 811)
  - United World Federalists, 1953-54 (Box 812)
  - World Association of World Federalists (Box 813)
  - World Association of World Federalists (Box 814)
  - World Association of World Federalists (Box 815)
  - World Association of World Federalists (Box 816)
  - World Association of World Federalists, Pacem in Terris (Box 817)
  - Samuel Kress Foundation, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1970's (Box 818)
  - Samuel Kress Foundation, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1970's (Box 819)
  - Samuel Kress Foundation, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1970's (Box 820)
  - Samuel Kress Foundation, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1970's (Box 821)
  - Samuel Kress Foundation, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1970's (Box 822)
  - Samuel Kress Foundation, Charles Kettering Foundation, 1970's (Box 823)
  - Microfilms of Saturday Review subscriber lists (one box is empty) (Box 824)
  - Audio Tapes: Nehru (11 tapes) -, 1949 (Box 825)
  - Audio Tapes: Nehru (9 tapes) - plus 3 with no date listed., 1961 (Box 826)
  - Audio Tapes: (Box 827)
    - United Nations Association (5 reels), 1965
    - Gold Key Awards Banquet (2 reels), 1964
    - Juggernaut (2 reels) and one reel, 1963 undated
    - Oakland United Nations (4 reels), 1964
  - Audio Tapes: (Box 828)
    - "Presenting Albert Schweitzer" - WBUR Boston University Radio, 1956; (1 reel)
    - "The Making of Tomorrow" NC talk to Northeast Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1959; (2 reels)
    - Last Lecture - Tallahassee, Jan. 31, 1963; (2 reels)
    - Florida Club Interview, (2 reels)
    - Haile Selassie I University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1961; (2 reels)
    - Dorothy Gordon Youth Forum, 1969; (2 reels)
    - Pacific School of Religion, 1959; (2 reels)
  - Audio Tapes: (Box 829)
    - Centenary College for Women, 1962; (1 reel)
    - Newark State College, 1963; (1 reel)
    - Oberlin College (Schweitzer), 1962; (1 reel)